The Bailey Collection
The Bailey Collection
- Notes on persons and places arranged alphabetically, 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9-C.7.18; GB/418/Bailey/1; 12 sub-series; Chetham's Library
  - Names and places beginning with F, 19th century; GB/418/C.7.12; GB/418/Bailey/1/6; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the Falconer family copied from theGentleman's Magazine., 1839; GB/418/C.7.12 no 16; GB/418/Bailey/1/6/4; Chetham's Library
    - Copy of the "Petition from the inhabitants of Farndon Churton Aldford to suffer John Boswell to use his Corricles over Dee in this tyme of Danger"., (7 Jun 1645); GB/418/C.7.12 no 17 (a); GB/418/Bailey/1/6/5; Chetham's Library
      19th century copy.
    - Extracts from the Registers of Farnworth Chapel from 1538 to 1577, with a sketch pedigree of the Farnworth family., 12 Jun 1879; GB/418/C.7.12 no 17 (b); GB/418/Bailey/1/6/6; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on Christopher Feake, who edited Mr Tillinghast's Eight Last Sermons whilst a prisoner in Windsor Castle in 1655., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.12 no 18; GB/418/Bailey/1/6/7; Chetham's Library
    - Notes concerning Daniel Featley., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.12 no 19; GB/418/Bailey/1/6/8; Chetham's Library
      Also State Papers Domestic Car II To the King's Most Excellent Majesty the Humble Petition of John Fairclough vulgo Featley.
    - Notes and correspondence concerning Dr John Ferriar., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.12 no 20; GB/418/Bailey/1/6/9; Chetham's Library
      Includes proof copies of articles relating to Ferriar:Memoir of Ferriar.
      Cutting fromPalatine Note-Book, 'The Bibliomania: An Epistle to Richard Heber Esq by John Ferriar, MD', 1 Mar 1882.
    - Notes and correspondence relating to the Finmore family., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.12 no 21; GB/418/Bailey/1/6/10; Chetham's Library
      Includes a pedigree, (1646-1695).
    - Notes on William Finney of Wilmslow, co Ches., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.12 no 22; GB/418/Bailey/1/6/11; Chetham's Library
    - Notes labelled "Fitchett", concerning his epic poem., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.12 no 23; GB/418/Bailey/1/6/12; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on Richard Fleming, Bishop of Lincoln., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.12 no 24; GB/418/Bailey/1/6/13; Chetham's Library
    - List of books relating to Simon Ford compiled by Anthony Wood., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.12 no 25; GB/418/Bailey/1/6/14; Chetham's Library
    - Copy of the will of Richard Fox of Manchester., (1655); GB/418/C.7.12 no 26; GB/418/Bailey/1/6/15; Chetham's Library
    - Letter from J. Herbert Kidson to J. E. Bailey concerning [Eliezer] Furness (born 1647)., 17 Aug 1885; GB/418/C.7.12 no 27; GB/418/Bailey/1/6/16; Chetham's Library
      Printed copy of 'A Sermon Preached at the Funeral of the Honorable Sir Robert Leicester of Tabley, Bart At Great Budworth in the county Palatine of Chester, July 11, 1684, by E Foreness, Presbyter of the Church of England' (London, 1684).
    - Notes on Furness Abbey., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.12 no 28; GB/418/Bailey/1/6/17; Chetham's Library
  - Names and places beginning with G, 19th century; GB/418/C.7.12; GB/418/Bailey/1/7; Chetham's Library
    - List of names from Garside to Guy., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.12 no 29; GB/418/Bailey/1/7/1; Chetham's Library
    - 19th century transcript of a Latin document concerning Henry Garside of Saddleworth., (1596/7); GB/418/C.7.12 no 30; GB/418/Bailey/1/7/2; Chetham's Library
    - Notes and correspondence concerning the Gee family., 1877-1878; GB/418/C.7.12 no 31; GB/418/Bailey/1/7/3; Chetham's Library
      Includes printed pamphlet, 'Mr Beaumont's History of Winwick: Charles Herle and the Gee Family', by J. E. Bailey FSA (Manchester, Jan 1879). Reprinted from theManchester Courier, 13 Dec 1878.
      Sketch pedigree of the family of Gee.
      Printed article, 'The Life of a Lancashire Rector during the Civil War' by J. E. Bailey FSA. Read at Winwick Oct 1877.
    - Notes concerning John Gibbon, with copies of two of Gibbon's letters., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.12 no 32; GB/418/Bailey/1/7/4; Chetham's Library
    - Two letters from J[?] Nicholson to J. E. Bailey concerning Robert Gibson, Recorder of Lancaster (died 1731)., 16 & 24 Aug 1883; GB/418/C.7.12 no 33; GB/418/Bailey/1/7/5; Chetham's Library
      With notes.
    - Notes and cuttings concerning John de Gigles, Archdeacon of Gloucester from 1488/9 to 1493., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.12 no 34; GB/418/Bailey/1/7/6; Chetham's Library
    - Notes concerning the diary of Mrs Goldbourne of Salford, with a transcript of a number of pages from the diary (1756)., 1885; GB/418/C.7.12 no 35; GB/418/Bailey/1/7/7; Chetham's Library
      Copy of the will of Margaret Goulbourn (sic), (19 Oct 1756).
      Two letters from William Harrison to J. E. Bailey concerning the diary, 28 & 30 Jul 1885.
      Copy of a letter from Roger Gilbody to Mrs Kelsall, (7 Jan 1745/6).
      Notes on the Goldborne family.
    - Notes, cuttings and letters concerning Oliver Goldsmith., 1885; GB/418/C.7.12 no 36; GB/418/Bailey/1/7/8; Chetham's Library
      Includes an extract fromThe Athanaeum on 'The Vicar of Wakefield' by Oliver Goldsmith, 26 Dec 1885.
    - Correspondence, notes and sketch pedigree concerning Christopher Goodman (16th century) and his family., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.12 no 37; GB/418/Bailey/1/7/9; Chetham's Library
    - Notes and correspondence relating to Gorton, co Lancs., [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.12 no 38; GB/418/Bailey/1/7/10; Chetham's Library
      Includes an extract from Duchy of Lancaster Pleadings, Elizabeth - Vol. 112.
    - Transcripts of letters from James Gosnell (one dated 8 May 1578), taken from the Baker MSS vol. 32 pp 436-437., 1879; GB/418/C.7.12 no 39; GB/418/Bailey/1/7/11; Chetham's Library
      With a letter from Alfred Rogers, University of Cambridge, 31 Jan 1879.
    - Notes on Rev Stanley Gower (17th century)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.12 no 40; GB/418/Bailey/1/7/12; Chetham's Library
    - Notes and correspondence relating to Valentine Greatrakes (d 1683)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.12 no 41; GB/418/Bailey/1/7/13; Chetham's Library
      Includes a proof copy of an article by J. E. Bailey, 'Andrew Marvell and Valentine Greatraks, the Stoker'.
    - Correspondence and cuttings relating to William Green, JP, of Poulton Lancelyn, co Ches, (17th century)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.12 no 42; GB/418/Bailey/1/7/14; Chetham's Library
    - Notes containing reference to Gressingham, co Lancs., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.12 no 43; GB/418/Bailey/1/7/15; Chetham's Library
    - Notes and correspondence relating to Prince Griffin, who appeared in a number of 17th century tracts., 19th cnetury; GB/418/C.7.12 no 44; GB/418/Bailey/1/7/16; Chetham's Library
    - Letter from J[?] Nicholson to J. E. Bailey concerning Henry Guy and William Guy., 16 Oct 1882; GB/418/C.7.12 no 45; GB/418/Bailey/1/7/17; Chetham's Library
  - Names and places beginning with H, [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.13; GB/418/Bailey/1/8; Chetham's Library
    - List of names from Hanby to Huyton., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 1; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/1; Chetham's Library
    - Letter from John Henn to J. E. Bailey requesting information about Richard Hanby., 1886; GB/418/C.7.13 no 2; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/2; Chetham's Library
      With newspaper cutting of the obituary of Richard Hanby, assistant librarian of Chetham's Library and House Governor of Chetham's College.
    - Notes and letters concerning the Hardman family., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 3; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/3; Chetham's Library
      With a sketch pedigree showing the descent from Samuel Hardman of Derbyshire (d 1695).
    - Notes labelled "Harrald", mostly shorthand., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 4; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/4; Chetham's Library
    - Notes headed "A Full Account of Mr John Harris, the English Hermit" (b 1710)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 5; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/5; Chetham's Library
    - Letter from [?] and D. Bennett to J. E. Bailey relating to W. Harris'sPharmacologies., 29 & 30 Mar 1886; GB/418/C.7.13 no 6; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/6; Chetham's Library
      Pharmacologies
    - Copy made by J. E. Bailey of a letter he sent to [M. J.] Owen, asking if he knows the birth date of Samuel Haward of Salford (d 1705)., 12 Feb 1883; GB/418/C.7.13 no 7; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/7; Chetham's Library
    - Notes concerning the Hartley family of Manchester., 17th century & 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 8; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/8; Chetham's Library
      With sketch pedigree showing the descent from Thomas Hartley of Moss Side Green (d 1592). Includes original 17th century document concerning court leet business, with mention of John Hartley, gent, constable of Manchester in 1629.
    - Material concerning Philip and Matthew Henry, (17th century)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 9; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/9; Chetham's Library
      'Philip and Matthew Henry. A Paper', read by the Rev. Matthew Henry Lee before the Chester Archaeological, Architectural and Historic Society, 9 Apr 1882.
      Proof review of article on 'Diaries and Letters of Philip Henry, M.A.'
      Letters relating to the Henrys.
    - Copy of Thomas Henshaw's will dated 14 Nov 1807., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 10; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/10; Chetham's Library
      Transcript concerning the petition of Hugh Henshaw, minister of the chapelry of Sankie, co Lancs, to the Commissioners for Compounding, (1653).
    - Notes, letters and impressions of seals relating to the Herbert family of Llanarth., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 11; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/11; Chetham's Library
    - Transcript of a memorial to George Herbert erected 1861., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 12; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/12; Chetham's Library
    - Notes and letters concerning Richard and Thomas Hesketh of Rufforth, and a sketch pedigree of the Hesketh family., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 13; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/13; Chetham's Library
    - Transcripts of documents concerning Ralph Heton and Christopher Anderton., (1576) & (1589); GB/418/C.7.13 no 14; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/14; Chetham's Library
      From Ralph Heton to Christopher Anderton, general release of all claims (1576).
      From Ralph and Richard Heton to James and Thurstan Anderton, bond for Mary Heton (their mother) to claim no dower, (1589).
      Torn, handle with care.
    - Notes, letters and cuttings concerning Peter Heylin, (also Heylyn) "an English miscellaneous writer" (b 1600)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 15; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/15; Chetham's Library
    - MISSING: Notes on R. Heyrick and a sketch pedigree of the Heyrick family [1664-1795?], 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 16; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/16; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the lives of Oliver and Nathaniel Heywood from 1629., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 17; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/17; Chetham's Library
    - Letter from James E. Worsley to J. E. Bailey asking if he has any information on John Worsley., 24 Oct 1879; GB/418/C.7.13 no 18; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/18; Chetham's Library
      With sketch pedigree of the Heywood family.
    - Notes concerning James Hyat, vicar of Croston, co Lancs, and the Hiet family., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 19; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/19; Chetham's Library
      Transcription from State Papers Domestic Car I, "The Complainte of many of the clergie of Lancashire ag[ains]t ye partiall and unequall Taxacon toward[es] this shipmony taxed on them by their assessors...The complaint of James Hyat".
    - Notes and letters concerning Bishop Hildersley (also Hildesley), Bishop of the Isle of Man., 1886; GB/418/C.7.13 no 20; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/20; Chetham's Library
      Includes proof copies of article by J. E. Bailey, 'The First Book Printed in Manx'.
    - Notes on Dr Hinde, mainly in shorthand., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 21; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/21; Chetham's Library
    - Notes, letters and sketch pedigree concerning John Hodgson Hinde, antiquary of the North of England (b 1806)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 22; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/22; Chetham's Library
      Also relating to Harrison, Houghton and Richard Longdon.
    - Notes on Samuel Hinde BD, (17th century)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 23; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/23; Chetham's Library
    - Notes and letters concerning the Hodgkinson family., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 24; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/24; Chetham's Library
      With pedigree (1542-1711).
    - Brief notes on letters of attorney relating to Richard Houghton and the Houghton family., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 25; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/25; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the Holbrooke family, with sketch pedigree showing the descent from Edward Holbrooke of Manchester (d 1656)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 26; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/26; Chetham's Library
    - Notes and letters concerning the Holcroft family., 1882; GB/418/C.7.13 no 27; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/27; Chetham's Library
    - Notes and letters concerning John Holker and the Holker family., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 28; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/28; Chetham's Library
      With sketch pedigrees.
    - Notes and letter concerning Raphael Holinshed (d 1580), author ofThe Chronicles., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 29; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/29; Chetham's Library
      The Chronicles
    - Notes on Rev Richard Hollinworth (born 1607), author ofMancuniensis., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 30; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/30; Chetham's Library
      Mancuniensis
    - Notes and letter concerning Thomas Holland and family., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 31; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/31; Chetham's Library
      Includes copy of the will of Thomas Holland, (18 Jun 1675).
    - Notes concerning the Holt(e) family., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 32; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/32; Chetham's Library
      With sketch pedigree.
    - Notes, letters and cuttings relating to Rev William (b 1600) and Rev John Hooke (b 1634)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 33; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/33; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on Jeremiah Horrox and William Crabtree, astronomers., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 34; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/34; Chetham's Library
      Letters relating to articles by J. E. Bailey.
      Proof copies of articles on Horrox and Crabtree.
      Sketch pedigrees of the families of Horrox and Crabtree.
      2 proof copies of 'The Writings of Jeremiah Horrox and William Crabtree, observers of the transit of Venus, 24 November 1639 with a bibliography of Horrox's Opera Posthuma &c', by John E. Bailey FSA, (Manchester, 1883). Reprinted fromThe Palatine Note-Book of Dec 1882 and Jan 1883.
      One copy of 'The Field Naturalist and Scientific Student', November 1882, containing an article by Prof William Harkness entitled 'Transits of Venus'.
    - Notes and letters concerning Rev John Howe, (17th century)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 35; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/35; Chetham's Library
      Proof copy of article by J. E. Bailey, 'John Howe's connection with Lancashire'.
    - Notes concerning James Howell, (17th century)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 36; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/36; Chetham's Library
    - Notes and letters concerning Dr John Hull of Manchester and the sale of his medical library in 1838., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 37; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/37; Chetham's Library
    - Transcript concerning the rectory of Huyton, taken from documents of the "Commissioners for Compounding Deeds & Settlements for Augmentation of Ministers livings, 1654"., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.13 no 38; GB/418/Bailey/1/8/38; Chetham's Library
  - Names and places beginning with I, J, K and L, [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.14; GB/418/Bailey/1/9; Chetham's Library
    - Letters and abstracts of deeds dating from 13th-17th centuries relating to Ightenhill (near Burnley)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 1; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/1; Chetham's Library
    - Notes and letter concerned with John Ireland (d 1614) and Thomas Ireland of Bewsey (d 1638)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 2; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/2; Chetham's Library
      With details of the order of the funeral of Thomas and his wife.
    - Notes on the career and publications of Thomas Jackson DD, 17th century divine., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 3; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/3; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the history of the Johnson family of Tildesley (Tyldesley) co Lancs during the 17th and 18th centuries., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 4; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/4; Chetham's Library
    - Extracts from an indenture between James Johnson of Salford, haberdasher, and Samuel Lowe of Middlewich et al concerning land in Deansgate., (4 Jul 1690); GB/418/C.7.14; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/5; Chetham's Library
    - Transcript of the petition of Richard Johnson, Fellow of Manchester Collegiate Church, to the Archbishop of Canterbury, (17th century)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 6; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/6; Chetham's Library
    - Transcript of the epitaph of Samuel Johnson, author ofHurlothrumbo [not the lexicographer], (d 1780)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 7; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/7; Chetham's Library
      Hurlothrumbo
    - Notes on the career of Thomas Johnson, clerk at Bolton and Deane, (fl 17th century)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 8; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/8; Chetham's Library
    - Notes, letters and sketch pedigrees, including details of William Jollie, 17th century nonconformist minister., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 9; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/9; Chetham's Library
      Includes 'A Funeral Sermon for that Pious Gentlewoman, Mrs. Eliz. Jollie, of Attercliffe who deceas'd Jan. 17. 1708/9' by W. Bagshaw (London, 1709).
    - Details of the will of Edmund Jones (1624-1674) of Barton Upon Irwell, co Lancs, nonconformist minister of Eccles, ejected 1662., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 10; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/10; Chetham's Library
    - Letter from W. [Reynell] to J. E. Bailey concerning Thomas Jones (d 1619)., 16 Jun 1885; GB/418/C.7.14 no 10(i); GB/418/Bailey/1/9/11; Chetham's Library
      Memorial card for Thomas Jones, Chetham's Librarian, (d 1875).
    - Envelope containing miscellaneous notes., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 10(ii); GB/418/Bailey/1/9/12; Chetham's Library
      Notes relating to:
      Illingworth, Margaret
      Ingham of Ribchester
      River Irwell
      Jorden family
      Joceline, Ellen
      "Jacks"
      Jackson, Anastasius
      Jackson, Elizabeth
      Jackson, John
    - Letter from W. E. [?Worden] to J. E. Bailey enclosing a photograph of the cover of Thomas a Kempis'sDe Imitatione Christi at the Royal Library in Brussels., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 11; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/13; Chetham's Library
      De Imitatione Christi
    - Manuscript notes concerning the history of Kersal, especially Kersal Cell and its owners., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 12; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/14; Chetham's Library
    - Transcription of proceedings concerning the tithes of Kirkham Parish in 1660., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 13; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/15; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the career and writing of Archippus Kippax, 17th century Lancashire clergyman., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 14; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/16; Chetham's Library
    - Envelope containing miscellaneous notes., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 14(i); GB/418/Bailey/1/9/17; Chetham's Library
      Relating to:
      Kay, Richard
      Kelsall, Theophilus
      Kelly of Manchester
      Kermehey, Roger de
      Keyt, WE
      King, Joseph
      King's preachers
      King's Vale Royal
      Knolles, Sir Robert
      Knutsford
      Knowsley, papers at
      Kuerden, Dr
    - Notes concerning the family and career of Henry de Lacy, Earl of Lincoln, (d 1348)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 15; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/18; Chetham's Library
    - Letter from [?] Napie[?r] to J. E. Bailey concerning a pamphlet by Edward Lane., 16 Feb 1879; GB/418/C.7.14 no 16; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/19; Chetham's Library
    - Notes concerning Samuel Langley of Swettenham co Ches and his father Thomas, parson of Middlewich co Ches (d 1657)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 17; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/20; Chetham's Library
    - Notes by R. Langton concerning bells at Manchester Town Hall., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 18; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/21; Chetham's Library
    - Letter from Robert Langton to J. E. Bailey, with newspaper cutting concerning William Langton., 7 Oct 1881; GB/418/C.7.14 no 19; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/22; Chetham's Library
    - Letter from Robert Lansdale to J. E. Bailey concerning the life and family of Thomas Lansdale of Worsley, (fl 17th century)., 26 Oct 1882; GB/418/C.7.14 no 20; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/23; Chetham's Library
    - Rubbings from the gravestone of the Lathom family., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 21; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/24; Chetham's Library
    - Notes and letters on the history of the Lawrence family of co Bucks and elsewhere., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 22; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/25; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the career of John Lees, Lancashire clergyman of 17th century, taken from Raines Lancashire Manuscripts vol 1, p 273., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 23; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/26; Chetham's Library
    - Notes, letters and cuttings on the life, career and writings of Charles Leigh, physician and naturalist., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 24; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/27; Chetham's Library
      With notes on the Leigh family.
    - Inventory of the goods of Theophilus Leigh of Singleton Grange co Lancs, gent (d 1662)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 25; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/28; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the funeral procession and family of Sir Peter Leigh (Legh) of Lyme co Ches (d 1635)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 26; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/29; Chetham's Library
    - Notes and letters concerning Sir Ashton Lever., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 27; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/30; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the writings of John Lewis, vicar of Preston, co Lancs, in the early 17th century., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 28; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/31; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the writings and career of John Ley, vicar of Budworth in the early 17th century., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 29; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/32; Chetham's Library
    - Notes, letters and cuttings on the life and career of Sir Peter Leycester of Tabley, 17th century historian., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 30; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/33; Chetham's Library
      Extracts relating to him fromThe GuardianandLocal Gleanings(Manchester CourierandLancashire General Advertiser, 1878).
      Leycester pedigree back to 13th century.
      Epilogue to 'Taming of the Shrew' enacted at Tabley House in 1671.
      Photographs of portrait of Sir Peter Leycester.
      17th century manuscript possibly written by Sir Peter Leycester: extracts from the works of John Williams and John Flavell.
    - Transcription of Latin charter relating to Leyland, co Lancs, with cutting 'Interesting Discoveries At The Old Hall'., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 31; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/34; Chetham's Library
    - Notes and cuttings on the career of Thomas Linacre of Wigan co Lancs, rector and founder of the Royal College of Physicians, (c 1460-1524)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 32; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/35; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the career of Thomas Linnett, 17th century scholar., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 33; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/36; Chetham's Library
    - Large collection of miscellaneous notes and extracts concerning the history of Liverpool and its inhabitants., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 34; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/37; Chetham's Library
      Extracts from 16th century Duchy Court cases relating to the town. Extracts from manor court rolls.
    - Notes on the career of John Livingston, clergyman in Scotland and Ireland (17th century)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 35; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/38; Chetham's Library
    - Notes concerning the Lloyd family., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 36; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/39; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on London booksellers' signs., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 37; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/40; Chetham's Library